Approach Archives
Approach Archives
- APPROACH files
  - Miscellaneous
    - Carleton Miscellany, Spring 1966 issue on Little Mags, APPROACH in (Box 4)
    - Circulars, rejections, come-ons of other magazines (Box 4)
    - Clippings for reference (Box 4)
    - COSMPE (Conference of Small Mag/Press Editors) (Box 4)
    - Contacts: Spanish and Portuguese, Brazilian (Box 4)
    - Contest announcements from other magazines (Box 4)
    - Coordinating Council of Literary Magazines (Box 4)
    - Correspondence with bookstores (Box 4)
    - Editorial discussions and decisions, 1958-1966; 9 folders (Box 4)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 4)
    - History of APPROACH, early, unpublished, evaluation by editors (Box 4)
    - Johnson Reprint Corporation (Box 4)
    - Kraus Reprint Corporation (Box 4)
    - Letters from other editors, concerning copyright, lists, acquiring take-over, praise for 10th Anniversary issue #23 Spring, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Letters to lapsed subscribers and would-be contributors, pre-1962; 1962-1965; 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Libraries, correspondence with (Box 5)
    - Listing of manuscripts received, 1967 (Box 5)
    - Little magazine exhibits (Box 5)
    - Lists of friends of accepted authors as tentative subscribers, 1957-[1962]; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Little magazine of the month club (Box 5)
    - Magazine distributors (Box 5)
    - Prospective subscribers names
      - Friends meetings lists (Box 5)
      - Learned societies and Poet and Critic lists (Box 5)
    - National Association of College Stores (Box 5)
    - National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities (Box 5)
    - New York State Council on the Arts (Box 5)
    - Nominations (Box 5)
    - Philadelphia Inquirer article, 8 Jan 1967 (Box 5)
    - APPROACH policy (Box 5)
    - Press announcements received (Box 5)
    - Requests for exchanges from other magazines (Box 5)
    - Requests for information for articles and bibliographies of little mags (Box 5)
    - Exchange lists (Box 5)
    - Requests for sample copies and back issues (Box 5)
    - Submissions, 1955-1967; 13 folders (Box 5)
    - Writers' conferences, 1958-1964; contacts and correspondence; 9 folders (Box 5)
- Books
  - Published works
    [This subseries includes] published works of our contributors, plus those books judged important for understanding the period from 1947-1967. The items starred are not to be included in the Approach archives. The starred books are standard works but the starred copies have our notations, etc.
    - Bartlett, Elizabeth BEHOLD THIS DREAMER Editorial Jus, S. A., Mexico City, 1959; "Review Copy" written in Bartlett's writing on fly-leaf (Box 6)
    - Bartlett Elizabeth POETRY CONCERTO Vagrom Chap Book #7, Flushing, N.Y., 1961 (Box 6)
    - Bell, Charles G. DELTA RETURN Indiana University Press, Bloomington, Ind., 1956; mimeographed and inscribed copy of "The Number of My Loves" to Philip Silver (Box 6)
    - Baum, Robert ORPHEUS AND OTHER POEMS Odyssey Chapbook #2, Chicago, Ill., 1959; review notice (Box 6)
    - Bly, Robert "A Broadsheet Against The New York Times Book Review" The Sixties Press, Madison, Minn., 10/10/61; with publication notice (Box 6)
    - Bradley, Sam ALEXANDER AND ONE WORLD South and West, Inc. Fort Smith, Ark., 1966; also South & West catalogue (Box 6)
    - Creagh, Patrick, Norman Porter, Desmond O'Grady POEMS Poetry, Rome, Italy, 1960; read in the Roman Theatre at Tusculum on Friday June 24th, 1960 (Box 6)
    - Creagh, O Criadain, O'Grady, [no title?], presented in a public reading at the American Academy in Rome on May 16 1959 inscribed by George Garrett with an invitation to the reading (Box 6)
    - Fairburn, A. R. D. THE DISADVANTAGES OF BEING DEAD and other sharp verses The Mermaid Press Wellington, New Zealand, 1958; including "Horse Pansies" and an afterword to the author by D. G. with press announcement (Box 6)
    - Fandel, John GLEANINGS The Turner Press Yonkers, N.Y., 1966; inscribed to Helen Fowler by the author (Box 6)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence "Christ Climbed Down" from A CONEY ISLAND OF THE MIND, New Directions Publishing Corp, N.Y. 1953, Christmas 1967; reprint in church bulletin (Box 6)
    - Fowler, Albert FOOLS ISLAND (Edmonds revision), 1967; mimeographed, one of 30 copies made up from original run of 100 copieswith new pages added and one of 3 copies bound Dec. 27, 1967 for private circulation only (Box 6)
    - Fowler, Albert FOOLS ISLAND, 1967; mimeographed, one of 100 copies originally run off for private circulation only, reduced by 30 for the Edmonds revision, single copy bound Dec. 27, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Fowler, Albert THE FISH GOD OF YOU FOOL, 1963; 1967; one of 25 copies stenciled and run off on Women Strike for Peace mimeograph by Forrest Coburn, September, 1963, and one of 3 bound Dec. 27, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Fowler, Albert TWO TRENDS IN MODERN QUAKER THOUGHT: a statement of belief Pendle Hill Publications, Wallingford, Pa., 1961 (Box 6)
    - Gonzalez-Gerth, Miguel DESERT SEQUENCE and other poems Nonpareil Press, 1956; inscribed to the Fowlers by the author (Box 6)
    - Gonzalez-Gerth, Miguel "The Image of Spain in American Literature, 1815-1865" reprinted from Journal of Inter-American Studies, Vol IV, No. 2, April, 1962; reprint; inscribed to the Fowlers by the author (Box 6)
    - Gonzalez-Gerth, Miguel co-translator with Robert C. Stephenson of Guillermo de Torre's "Contemporary Spanish Poetry" reprinted from The Texas Quarterly Special Issue "Image of Spain," Spring 1961 (Box 6)
    - Gonzalez Gerth, Miguel THE INFINITE ABSENCE The Books Stall, Austin, Texas, 1955; inscribed to the Fowlers by the author (Box 6)
    - Gonzalez Gerth, Miguel, co-compiler with Geoffrey Connell POETRY AT THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS, 1953 University of Texas Press, Austin, Texas, 1954; #488 of 500 (Box 6)
    - Lyttle, David THE RE-ENTRY and other poems Goostree Press, Lanham, Md., 1964 (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "Introduction to Ascetical & Mystical Theology", 1931; mimeographed, lectures given at the Abbey of Gethsemani (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "Christian Worship and Social Reform", undated; mimeographed at the Abbey, not for publication (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "The Climate of Monastic Prayer" Abbey of Gethsemani Novitiate, 1964 (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas, "A Devout Meditation in Memory of Adolf Eichmann" Mimeographed at the Abbey, undated (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "Mystics and Zen Masters", undated; mimeographed at the Abbey, not for publication (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "The Name of the Lord" Abbey of Gethsemani, 1963; mimeographed (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "Peace in the Post Christian Era", mimeographed at the Abbey, with notation by Albert Fowler that he received it from the author June 1962 (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "Selections on Prayer" Choir Novitiate, Gethsemani, 1961; mimeographed (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "Preface to Japanese Edition of The Seven Storey Mountain", undated; mimeographed at the Abbey (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "A Ruler's Examination of Conscience: some texts from Francois Fenelon", undated; mimeographed at the Abbey (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "St. Anselm & His Argument" Gethsemani, 1963; mimeographed (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "The Tragedy of Father Perrin", 1964; mimeographed at the Abbey (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "Boris Pasternak and the people with watch chains" reprinted from Jubilee, July, 1959 (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "Notes on sacred and profane art" (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "A Martyr for Peace and Unity: Father Max Josef Metzger: 1867-1944" (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "Target Equals City" (Box 6)
    - Merton, Thomas "Christian Action in World Crisis" (Box 6)
    - Morgenstern, Christian GALLOWS SONGS University of Michigan Press, Ann Arbor, Mich., 1967; translated by Snodgrass, W.D. with Lore Segal; illustrations by Paul Klee; with publication notice (Box 6)
  - Reference works
    [This subseries contains] indices, bound volumes of out-of-print little magazines of the preceding generation, histories of little magazines, general works of reference and anthologies, etc.
    - The Magazine: A Literary Journal bound copies of #1-#6, The Magazine Corporation, Beverly Hills, Calif., 1933-1935 (Box 6)
      Volume I, Dec. 1933-May 1934
      Volume II, Nos. 2-6 July 1934-June 1935
    - POETRY, 1913-1922; 1 volume (Box 6)
      covers the following years:
      Vol. II No. 3, June, 1913
      Vol. IV No. 5, Aug. 1914
      Vol. VI, No. 6, Sept. 1915
      Vol. VIII No. 2, May, 1916
      Vol. X No. 1, April 1917
      Vol. XII, No. 6, Sept. 1918
      Vol. XV, No. 2, Nov. 1919
      Vol. XVI, No. 4, July 1920
      Vol. XVIII, No. 4, July 1921
      Vol. I, No. 2, Nov. 1922
    - Twice A Year: a semi-annual journal of literature, the arts, and civil liberties special double number Nos. 3-4, Fall-Winter 1939; Dorothy Norman, editor (Box 6)
    - Twice A Year: A book of literature, the arts and civil liberties, No. VII, Fall-Winter, 1941 (Box 6)
  - Vanity press items
    [This subseries contains] material from the vanity presses, being the only evidence of poetry we found unacceptable, since rejected mss to the authors, with the few exceptions where the Post Office returned them to us because the address was no good.
    - Barbarash, Robert DOME IN AIR Holly Pond Press, Stamford, Conn., 1962; with letter from author (Box 7)
    - Katz, Menke LAND OF MANNA Windfall Press, Chicago, 1965; with letter to APPROACH editors from author, dated 9/27/65 (Box 7)
- Magazines
  - Complete files of our exchanges
    - AGENDA, 1961-1966; British, 12 issues a year, William Cookson editor, Oxford; 8 issues (Box 7)
      Vol 2, no 4, June 1961, no 5, Sept-Oct 1961
      Vol 2 no 6 Mar 1962, nos 9 & 10 combined Sep-Oct. 1962
      Vol 3, no 4 Apr. 1964, no 6 Dec. 1964
      Vol 4, no 1 April-May 1965, no's 5 & 6 combined Autumn 1966
    - ART AND LITERATURE: an international review, 1964-1965; Lausanne Switzerland, John Ashbery editor; 2 issues (Box 7)
      number 3 autumn-winter 1964
      number 5 summer 1965
    - ODYSSEY REVIEW: a quarterly of modern Latin American and European literature in English translation, 1963; published by the Latin American & European Literary Society, Richmond, Va. Editor Saul Galin (Box 7)
      Vol 3 no 2 June 1963
    - PARIS REVIEW (THE), 1958; quarterly, publisher Sadruddin Aga Khan, editors: George A. Plimpton, Donald Hall among others, N.Y.; 2 issues (Box 7)
      no 18, Spr '58 (5th anniversary issue)
      no 19 Summer '58
    - UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS CITY REVIEW (THE), 1951-1967; later The University Review; quarterly journal to provide a medium for the best critical and imaginative writing available, Editors: Clarence R. Decker, John Ciardi among others; 64 issues (Box 7)
      Vol 18 no 1 Autumn '51; no 2 Winter '51; no 3 Spr '52; no 4 Summer '52
      Vol 19 no 1 Autumn '52; no 2 Winter '52; no 3 Spr '53; no 4 Summer '53
      Vol 20 no 1 Autumn '53; no 2 Winter '53; no 3 Spr '54; no 4 Summer '54
      Vol 21 no 1 Autumn '54; no 2 Winter '54; no 3 Spr '55; no 4 Summer '55
      Vol 22 no 1 Oct '55; no 2 Dec '55; no 3 Mar '56; no 4 June '56
      Vol 23 no l Oct '56; no 2 Dec '56; no 3 Mar '57; no 4 June '57
      Vol 24 no 1 Oct '57; no 2 Dec '57; no 3 Mar '58; no 4 June '58
      Vol 25 no 2 Dec '58; no 3 Mar '59; no 4 June '59
      Vol 26 no 1 Oct '59; no 2 Dec '59; no 3 Mar '60; no 4 June '60
      Vol 27 no 1 Oct '60; no 2 Dec '60; no 3 Mar '61; no 4 June '61
      Vol 28 no 1 Oct 181; no 2 Dec '61; no 3 Mar '62; no 4 June '62
      Vol 29 no 1 Oct '62; no 2 Dec '62; no 3 Mar '63; no 4 June '63
      Vol 30 no 1 Oct '63; no 2 Dec '63; no 3 Mar '64; no 4 June '64
      Vol 31 no 1 Oct '64; no 2 Dec '64; no 3 Mar '65; no 4 June '65
      Vol 32 no 1 Oct '65; no 2 Dec '65; no 3 Mar '66; no 4 June '66
      Vol 33 no 1 Oct '66; no 2 Dec '66; no 3 Mar '67; no 4 June '67
      Vol 34 no 1 Oct '67
    - VOICES: a journal of poetry, 1955-1965; Harold Vinal editor Vinalhaven, Maine; 30 issues (Box 8)
      no 156 Jan/Apr '55; no 157 May/Aug '55; no 158 Sept/Dec '55
      no 159 Jan/Apr '56; no 160 May/Aug '56; no 161 Sept/Dec '56
      no 162 Jan/Apr '57; no 163 May/Aug '57
      no 165 Jan/Apr '58; no 167 Sept/Dec '63
      no 168 Jan/Apr '59; no 169 May/Aug '59; no 170 Sept/Dec '59
      no 171 Jan/Apr '60; no 172 May/Aug '60; no 173 Sept/Dec '60
      no 174 Jan/Apr '61; no 175 May/Aug '61; no 176 Sept/Dec '61
      no 177 Jan/Apr '62; no 178 May/Aug '62; no 179 Sept/Dec '62
      no 180 Jan/Apr '63; no 182 Sept/Dec '63
      no 183 Jan/Apr '64; no 184 May/Aug '64; no 3 1964
      nos 1, 2 and 3 1965
    - WESTERN REVIEW: a literary quarterly, 1955-1956; published at the State University of Iowa, editors: Ray B. West, Jr. and Paul Engle, Iowa City; 4 issues (Box 8)
      Vol 19 no 2 Winter '55; no 3 Spring '55
      Vol 20 no 1 Autumn '55; no 2 Winter '56
    - WESTERN HUMANITIES REVIEW, 1956-1967; published by the University of Utah, quarterly Salt Lake City, Utah, editor William Mulder; 42 issues (Box 8)
      Vol 10 no 3 Summer 1956 with index for Vol 10
      Vol 11 no 1 Winter '57; no 2 Spr '57; no 3 Summer '57; with index for Vol 11
      Vol 12 no 1 Winter '58; no 2 Spr '58; no 3 Summer '58
      Vol 13 no 1 Winter '59; no 2 Spr '59; no 3 Summer '59; no 4 Autumn '59 with index to Vol 13
      Vol 14 no 1 Winter '60; no 2 Spr '60; no 3 Summer '60; no 4 Autumn '60 with index to Vol 14
      Vol 15 no 1 Winter '61; no 2 Spr '61; no 3 Summer '61; no 4 Autumn '61 with index to Vol 15
      Vol 16 no 1 Winter '62; no 2 Spr '62; no 3 Summer '62; no 4 Autumn '62
      Vol 17 no 1 Winter '63; no 2 Spr '63; no 3 Summer '63; no 4 Autumn '63 with index to Vol 17
      Vol 18 no 1 Winter '64; no 2 Spr '64; no 3 Summer '64; no 4 Autumn '64
      Vol 19 no 1 Winter '65; no 2 Spr '65; no 3 Summer '65; no 4 Autumn '65
      Vol 20 no 1 Winter '66; no 2 Spr '66; no 3 Summer '66; no 4 Autumn '66
      Vol 21 no 1 Winter '67; no 2 Spr '67; no 3 Summer '67
  - Miscellaneous magazines
    [This subseries contains] magazines that wished to exchange with us but we did not wish to exchange with, etc. Sometimes an established magazine sent us a copy or two.
    - AAUP Bulletin, Autumn issue, Sept. 1959; Vol 45 no 3 (Box 9)
    - ALBATROSS: an intercollegiate magazine of student letters, Nov 1960; Vol I no 1; Swarthmore College, Swarthmore, Pa. (Box 9)
    - AMERICA: National Catholic weekly review, April 20 1961; Vol 105, no 5; N.Y. (Box 9)
    - AMERICAN FARM & HOME ALMANAC, 1966; Ray Geiger, editor; Lewiston, Maine; with press release (Box 9)
    - AMERICAN SCHOLAR (THE): a quarterly for the independent thinker, 1956-1959; 3 issues; Vol 26 no 1, Winter 1956-57; Vol 28 no 3, Summer 1959; Vol 28 no 4, Autumn 1959; Hiram Haydn, editor, New Haven, Conn. (Box 9)
    - ANALYSIS: first conservative college magazine on the east coast, Summer, 1963; Vol 3 no 3; Philadelphia, Pa.; W.H. Regnery, Editor (Box 9)
    - ANGELS (THE), Spring 1966; Vol 3 no 1; Judson Dicks, editor, Central Islip, N.Y. (Box 9)
    - ARCHER (THE), Winter 1963; Vol 11 no 2; Wilfred and Elinor Henry Brown, owners, North Hollywood, Calif. (Box 9)
    - ATLANTIAN, Winter 1966; Vol 25 nos 3 & 4 (special art issue); Tony Aromanto, Editor, Atlanta, Ga. (Box 9)
    - AUTHOR & JOURNALIST, June 1964; Vol 64 no 6, (Poetry Market List issue) published by Vantage Press, Harold Ellithorpe, editor, N.Y. (Box 9)
    - BARDIC ECHOES: official publication of The Bards of Grand Rapids, Mich., 1962; 1964; Vol 3, no 3 Sept. 1962; Vol 5 no 1, March 1964; Vol 5 no 2, June 1964; Vol 5 no 3, Sept. 1964; Vol 5 no 4, Dec. 1964; Clarence L. Weaver, editor, Grand Rapids, Mich. (Box 9)
    - BARRYTOWN EXPLORER: Mid-Hudson Monthly All the News That's Fit to Print, 1964; Vol 6 no 12 May 1964, Vol 7 no 1 June 1964; Helen R. Chapman, editor, Barrytown, N.Y. (Box 9)
    - BETWEEN WORLDS: an international magazine of creativity, 1960-1962; Vol 1, Summer 1960, Gilbert Neiman, editor, published for the Inter-American University by Alan Swallow, San German, Puerto Rico & Boulder, Colo.; Vol 1 No, 2, 1961 with letter from Westwood Bookstore; Vol 2 no 1, 1962 (Box 9)
    - BLACKBIRD: quarterly magazine of letters & the arts, Winter 1963-1964; Vol 1 no 2, Eugene O. Cozzi, editor, Chicago, Ill. (Box 9)
    - BLACK TEAR (THE) an art magazine for promotion of good contemporary art, undated; Jay Kesselman editor, published by Black Tear/Goliards Press, Inc. Milwaukee Wis. (Box 9)
    - BLUE GUITAR: the journal of poetics, Spring 1960; no 17,; editor and publisher G. De Witt, North Long Beach, Calif. (Box 9)
    - BOOKS ABROAD: an international literary quarterly, 1954; 1959; Vol 28 no 4, Autumn 1954; Vol 33 No 3, Summer 1959; published by University of Oklahoma Press, Norman, Okla. Ernst Erich Noth, editor (Box 9)
    - BRIDGE (THE) le petit journal mimeographed., 1947; 1950,; 1953,; 1955; Vol 1 no 2, Aug 19, 1947; Vol 1 no 4, Sept 2 1947; Vol 5 no 1 Oct 1950; Vol 7 no 1, Jan 1953; Vol 9 no 4. Apr 1955; Glen Coffield, editor and publisher, Portland, Ore (Box 9)
    - Bryn Mawr-Haverford Revue, May 1959; editors Elizabeth Carr, Joanne Field, Cynthia Lovelace, Richard Patrick, Jayzee, Bryn Mawr, Pa. (Box 9)
    - California Quarterly (The) an independent publisher, 1956; Vol 4 no 1; Philip Stevenson, managing editor, Los Angeles, Calif. (Box 9)
    - CAMEL'S HUMP (THE), undated; poetry newsletter published occasionally by CAMELS COMING Nos. 1, 2, 3 (Box 9)
    - CARDINAL: The literary Magazine of Wesleyan University, Fall 1962; editor-in-chief, Stuart Byron, Middletown, Conn (Box 9)
    - CATHOLIC WORKER (THE), 1961-1962; 1965-1968; organ of the Catholic Worker movement, Peter Maurin, ed., N.Y. (Box 9)
      Vol 28 no 4, Nov '61; no 10 May '62
      Vol 32 no 4, Dec '65; no 5, Jan '66; no 6, Feb '66; no 7, Mar '66; no 8, Apr '66; no 9, May '66; no 10, Jun '66
      Vol 33 no 3, Dec '66; no 4, Jan '67; no 5 Feb '67; no 7, May '67; no 8, Jun '67; no 9 Jul-Aug '67; no 10, Sep '67; no 12, Dec '67
      Vol 34 no 1, Jan '68; no 2 Feb '68
    - CEA CRITIC (THE), 1961; 1964; official organ of the College English Assoc., A. Sears, editor Uppsala College, East Orange, N.J.; same editor moved to Skidmore College, Saratoga Springs NY. (Box 9)
      Vol 23 no 7, Oct. 1961; Vol 23 no 8, Nov. 1961; Vol 23 no 9, Dec 1961
      Vol 26 no 7, April 1964
    - CENTER DIARY: 12, May-June 1966; Center for the study of democratic institutions, Santa Barbara, Calif. Robert M. Hutchins, president (Box 9)
    - CHALLENGE: fostering unity in diversity among all peoples, Spring 1965; No. 19; science, religion, philosophy, the arts, human relations, Leland P. Stewart editor, Reseda, Calif. (Box 9)
    - CHAT NOIR REVIEW (THE), Dec. 1961; 1963; Vol 1 no 1; Vol 2 no 2; Robert Herron Ingalls, publisher and later editor, Edwin G. Schwenn, editor, Chicago, Ill. (Box 9)
    - CHICAGO REVIEW, Winter 1956; Spring 1956; Vol 9 no 4; Vol 10 no 1; University of Chicago; editors-in-chief: Blazer, Lachlan Macdonald (Box 9)
    - CHRISTIAN CHALLENGE (THE), 1966-1967; organ of the Brethren of Early Christianity, put out from the community farm of the Brethren, Bright, Ontario (Box 9)
      no 1, May 1966; no 2, June 1966; no 3, July 1966; no 4 Aug. 1966; no 5 Sept. 1966; no 6, Oct. 1966; no 7 Nov. 1966; no 3, Dec. 1966
      no 9, Jan 1967
    - CHRISTIANITY AND CRISIS: A Christian Journal of Opinion, Jan 22 1962; Vol 21 no 24; editors: Reinhold Niebuhr and John C. Bennett, N.Y. (Box 9)
    - CHURCH REVIEW (THE), organ of the Church Society for College Episcopal Cambridge, Mass. (Box 9)
      Vol 22 no 4, Sept. 1964
      Vol 23 nos 1 & 2, Feb.-Apr. 1965; no 3, May 1965; no 4, Sept. 1965; no 5 Nov. 1965; no 6, Dec 1965
      Vol 24 no 1, Feb. 1966; nos 2 & 3 Apr.-May 1968; no 4, Oct. 1966
      Vol 25 no 1, Aug. 1967
      Several occasional papers:
      Military Service in a Free Society
      The New Student
      Technology and Culture in Perspective
      Initiative in History: a Christian-Marxist Exchange
    - COLLEGE BOOKMAN (THE), Summer 1966; no. 8; edited by the librarian, Gene Magner, in Morrisville, State University of New York Agricultural and Technical College (Box 9)
    - COLORADO REVIEW (THE), Winter 1958-1959; Dept. of English, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, Colo. Editors: R. Collins ("Jay Pell") & F.M. Laticlais (Box 9)
    - COLORADO STATE REVIEW (THE), 1967; Vol 11 no 1; Colorado State University, Fort Collins, Colo. editor: Charles Robinson (Box 9)
    - COMMENT IN MOTION:, 1967; no. 2 and no. 4; translations: Grover Jacoby, Variegation Publishing Co. Los Angeles, Calif. with letter (Box 9)
    - CONNOTATION: a quarterly magazine of the arts, Spring 1962; Fairleigh Dickinson University, Madison, N.J. Stephen H. Goode, editor (Box 9)
    - CONTACT (incorporating Western Review, The San Francisco Collection of new writing, art and ideas), Jan/Feb 1964; Vol 4 no 3; editors: Kenneth Lamott; Calvin Kentfield, Evan S. Connel, Jr. Sausalito, Calif. (Box 9)
    - CREATIVITY NEWSLETTER, Feb. 25, 1964; #6; mimeographed, Glen Coffield, editor, Eugene Ore. (Box 9)
    - CREATIVE REVIEW (THE) a literary quarterly, 1960-1963; mimeographed, editor Glen Coffield Portland Ore. (Box 9)
      Vol 1 no 1, Winter 1960-1661; no 3, Summer 1961; no 4, Autumn 1961
      Vol 2 no 1, Winter 1961-1962; no 2 Spring 1962
      Vol 3 no 2, Spring 1963
    - CRIMSON AND GRAY: the literary journal of Saint Joseph's College, Spring 1964; Philadelphia, Pa. editor: William McLaughlin, annotated by editor (Box 9)
    - CRITIC (THE) a Catholic review of books and the arts, 1960; 1966; Vol 29 no 2, Oct.-Nov. 1960; reprint from Feb.-Mar. 1966 issue (Daniel Berrigan & Sister Mary Corita, I.H.M.); Paul K. Cuneo editor, Chicago, Ill (Box 9)
    - CRITICAL: a review of art and criticism, 1963; no. 6; published by Stuart Publications, Boston, Mass. (Box 9)
    - CROSS CURRENTS: a quarterly review to explore the implications of Christianity for our times, Winter 1958; Vol 8 no 1; editors: Joseph L. Caulfield, Sally S. Cunneen, Alfred di Lascia, Eugene Fontinell, Erwin Geissman, N.Y. City (Box 9)
    - CURRENT: the significant new material from all sources on the frontier problems of today, Nov. 1964; no 53; associate editors: Andrew E. Norman, Grant S. McClellan, Ira S. Glasser, N.Y. City (Box 9)
    - DECEMBER: a magazine of the arts and opinion, 1963; 1966; Vol 5 no 1, Vol 8 no 1; Curt Johnson editor (a letter from Johnson to Helen Fowler) Western Springs, Ill. (Box 10)
    - DEFINITION: a journal of events and aesthetic realism, 1963; , with broadside; Martha Baird editor (letter from M. Baird to Helen Fowler) put out by Definition Press, N.Y. City (Box 10)
    - DELAWARE VALLEY CALENDAR, Oct. 1967; Vol 6 no 10; David Rogers Crosby editor, inscribed to Helen Fowler by him, Camden, N.J. (Box 10)
    - DE PAUL LITERARY MAGAZINE (THE), Winter 1963; Spring 1964; from De Paul University, Chicago Ill. William J. Feeney, editor (Box 10)
    - DIE WELT DER LITERATUR, March 19, 1964; Vol 1 no 1; editor-in-chief Hans Zeher (Box 10)
    - EAST CAROLINA POETRY FORUM SERIES, Trio-in-blues, undated; no. 1; David Lawson, Laverne Manners, Woody Thurman, East Carolina University, Greenville, N.C. (Box 10)
    - EAST CAROLINA POETRY FORUM SERIES, Trio-in-gold, Chas Wiley, Barbara Knott; East Carolina University, Greenville, N.C. (Box 10)
    - EAST SIDE REVIEW: a magazine of contemporary culture, Jan-Feb 1966; Vol 1 no 1; S. Shepard Sherbell editor-publisher, N.Y. City (Box 10)
    - ELEGREBA (British), Spring 1959; no. 3; edited by Roye McCoye Stratton St. Margaret, Swindon, Wilts. (APPROACH plug) (Box 10)
    - ENCOUNTER (THE), 1963; 1966; Vol 5 no 1, Vol 5 no 2; edited by students of Saint Leo College, Saint Leo, Fla. letter from John Baerst advisor (Box 10)
    - ENVOI: a quarterly review of new poetry (British), undated; no 18; poem by S. Bradley p. 3; editor: E. Mackin, Cheltenham, Glos. (Box 10)